Today we are revisiting Häen's Belgian
chocolate cuz somebody mentioned it in
the comments and I love
it. Yep. This happens to be probably my
favorite Hagenars or storebought ice
cream available. The Hagen's Belgian
chocolate. It's super decadent. It's
creamy. It's got a milk chocolate
profile. It's got loads of flexcks of
Belgian chocolate in there. So, we're
going to make it again. Last time I made
it, I was back in England. This time I
am in Canada. So, let's get on and make
it. The most important ingredient in
this is your cocoa powder. And I happen
to find the exact flavor profile in
this. This cocoa powder gives you an
identical flavor to the Hagen's Belgian
chocolate. I get this in the UK and I
get my family to bring it over. I
haven't seen it in North America, but
it's worth if this Handal's Belgian
chocolate is your favorite flavor, it's
worth importing it from Amazon. So find
it, order it. There must be some other
ones out there that have this flavor.
It's a milk chocolate profile cocoa
powder. Okay, that's super important.
Don't use a dark chocolate profile
because it will not taste the same. It
will still taste good, but it's this is
an exact replica of the Handas Belgian
chocolate we are going for. Please make
sure to like this video. Really helps
YouTube know that people want to watch
it and it will help the channel grow
more. If you like ice cream, also make
sure to subscribe to the channel. This
is a 2 liter batch, so have it if you
want. Do what you need to do to make it
in the size tubs and containers that you
want. But we are starting off with our
cream, which is 840
g. I'm using 33% whipping cream. You can
use heavy cream. That is absolutely
fine. Anywhere 33, 36 is fine. If you're
in the
UK or in Europe, stick to double cream.
Go back to the original recipe because
that one is designed for you guys. This
one is for my North American family.
High. Into that, we're adding 640 ml of
whole
milk. Into that, we are adding 215 g of
sugar. 20 g of this is vanilla sugar. If
you don't have vanilla sugar, make the
whole thing normal sugar and add a
teaspoon of vanilla
extract, 100 g of skim milk
powder, 107 g of
dextrose. The the amount of dextrose is
important. Don't go messing that one up.
If you're going to use a stabilizer, add
it into your sugar or your
dextrose. If you're not going to use a
stabilizer, don't worry about it. In
that
goes. And stir it together. Right, with
that stirred together, we are not going
to add our cocoa powder just yet. We're
going to get this on a hob and get this
warming up. It's better to add cocoa
powder to hot liquid. So, we're going to
get up to 50°, which is this in
Fahrenheit. And then we're going to add
our cocoa powder and whisk it in. Right,
we're up to 45° C. This is the perfect
time to get our cocoa powder in.
Right, with that mixed in, you're still
going to find some lumps at 4550C, so
don't stress about it. That's going to
go back on the hob now and heat up to
85C because I'm using a stabilizer. If
you're not using a stabilizer, you still
need to get it up to about 60 65 C to
make sure that cocoa powder is fully
dissolved. Cocoa powder doesn't actually
dissolve in liquid. It just breaks apart
into individual particles and it looks
like it's dissolved. That's why when you
make something like a hot cocoa, the
cocoa solids actually sink to the
bottom. That's very normal. Just stir it
back up to a degree. You get that with
ice cream as well. And that's why you
generally add emulsifiers and
stabilizers to chocolate ice cream to
try and stop that
happening. All right, there we go. We
are up to
80C. Perfect temperature, perfect
consistency. Let's get this in a
container.
And I'm going to let this relax on the
surface for about 10 minutes. Then it's
going to go straight in the fridge
overnight. So now that our chocolate
base is completely chilled in the
fridge, we're just going to whisk that
back up. Make sure all those solids are
completely incorporated again into our
ice cream base. And we can put it into
our pre-chilled machine. I've had the
machine running for 10 minutes, which is
something I recommend you do anyway.
Pour it in because now it's time to get
our chocolate out. This is the chocolate
I am going to
use. Calibbo dark chocolate. This is a
70% chocolate. I recommend you go for
this one if you can. Over here in
Canada, they sell it in Safeway, but you
can buy it basically anywhere. Right at
the end of the churn, you are going to
take a spoon and just load in some of
your cho chopped chocolate pieces.
That's really difficult to say. And you
can put in as much or as little as you
want, but I recommend about 100 g of
chocolate per one liter of ice cream.
Now, it's just time to dish it up
because I am super desperate to try
this. But it does need to go back in the
freezer to properly harden off for a
minimum of 5 hours. Okay.
[Music]
Super good scoop. It smells delicious.
Texture looks so far amazing. What does
it taste
like? Honestly, this is perfect in
pretty much every single way. It's such
a good ice cream. Identical to the
Hagenars's Belgian chocolate, but a
better texture. And it's super easy to
make. There you go. I'm going to say
again, track that down. This cocoa
powder, if you like Hogen's Belgian
chocolate and you want to make it
exactly at home, you need that. You can
do some other things with this as well.
So, obviously we've got a standard Ninja
Creamy and Ninja Creamy
Deluxe. You can use your leftover
chocolate. You can spin that in there.
You can use coconut. So, you've got a
milk chocolate coconut. That would be
delicious as well. And you can also go
for the syrups, coffee syrups,
absolutely fine. Go for the higher sugar
ones because you don't want them to
freeze solid. This one, the Amarina
Fabri Fabry, this brand is the best
syrups on the market, hands down. So
that super nice
cherry swirled into a ninja creamy tub
of this chocolate ice cream base would
be amazing. Anyway, thanks very much for
watching. Don't forget to like and
subscribe. If you want to know about the
sciency side of this recipe, head over
to Patreon or become a YouTube member. I
upload now all the important scientific
info on there. I'm going to eat the rest
of this tub and I will see you next week
when I make this Hagen's key lime pie.
But we're going to do it better than
they have.